[Music]
Welcome back to my page and this is
growing race with KC and if this is your first time
here we are discussing the
uses of money Kara and dreams in
life and in this video we are going to
talk about basic life insurance
terminology and I believe that one
of the factors that affect the
decision-making of Filipinos when it
comes to life insurance in getting life
insurance is that Education about life
insurance and I hope that after watching
this video our
doubt about life insurance will be reduced because
we understand it better so first let
's talk about the
basic types of insurance so in
life insurance it is death that is the
most basic insurance when it
comes to protection if you die
unexpectedly so life insurance
will make sure that our loved ones
especially
our beneficiaries will get life
insurance when it comes to
investment link insurance this is more
of the retirement purposes no a portion
of your premium will go to the
investment no and so Through Time
it can grow grow your money
Okay so let's talk  about that in Our
next videos about investment link
insurance versus traditional insurance
There is insurance that focuses on
health no So it covers the medical
bills or Sickness and hospitalization
there is also Accidental death
insurance for examples for those
who are on the road like that
we have very cheap
Accidental death
insurance we also have auto
insurance auto insurance is
comprehensive insurance for those who are on the
road there is also home insurance so
home owners insurance or un forcing
events Like for example fire or
natural
disasters that cause our
house to be damaged So that's the home insurance
the basic non
terminologies that we hear When
we talk to a financial Planner
or financial advisor no So this video
aims that we don't get overwhelmed by
information and we don't get to focus on the
actual um design of the policy
but because we get over What does
he mean by this What does
this term mean So this video Uh will
make you understand this basic
terminologies of
insurance so First Policy no the
policies the policy that the insurance
itself you get insurance now that's the
policy that that's your insurance
insurance
policy at the premium  when you hear
the term premium it means
that's what you pay It could be
monthly It could be annually or
quarterly so it depends depends SAO no but
the amount no as I said in
my previous videos the amount of
our premium is not the same It
depends first on the insurance you choose
on the focus of the insurance
you choose it also depends on age
um on your risk in health conditions
like that So many things can affect the
premium So basically the premium is
what we pay monthly or
annually or
quarterly so when you hear
that not sure if the
terminology is the same with other insurance No
but after
the some assured When you say sum
assured That's the total coverage
cost that you set
supposedly this is what I want for ah death
benefit this is what I want for critical
illness this is what I want for
um Well first this is what you're supposed to do 500,000
for death benefit 500,000 for critical
illness Ah that's what you set
some assured the total no 1 million that
some assured that's what they'll take aside
there are bonuses as aside there are
cash values ​​no So what did
you set in the policy that is some
assured because you expected that
amount when something happened SAO
unexpectedly and then we will hear the
terms like policy holder insured and
beneficiary so these are the three people
within a policy or within
an insurance contract no the
policy holder or the policy owner is the one who
pays the premium he is the one who
applied no he is the one who will
talk to the financial
planner and then the insured is the one who
can cycle with
me the owner of the palis I will insure
my parents but the
beneficiary is different so that's it there is always that
So the beneficiary is the
only one who can claim
money when something happens to the insured
Okay always so we have something called
term insurance we also have something
called permanent insurance so
we discussed last time and
we will also have a separate video
discussing the pros and cons of
term insurance and permanent insurance
so the term insurance is the
insurance that only has specific years
You cover for example one year for
example in the one no it's only one year
So within 1 year you're only covered and
then there's permanent is
until you die that's for as long as
you live That's as long as you pay
your premium it won't be cut
No that means you are like forever
until you live you
are covered no as long as you are paying
your
premium All right so again The term
is there's a certain period of time that
you're only covered and then the permanent
is until you live you until
you can use it or there's permanent
life insurance that When you reach 75 and
you haven't claimed
your major critical illness or you haven't
claimed it
is You can
get it back you've
paid premiums when we heard the vul
that's what I was saying earlier variable
unit insurance or investment linked
insurance no so a portion of your
premium will go to the investment You
choose where you want to
invest it All right and the traditional
one is there's no investment involved
nothing it's purely
protection it's just Okay and then p
also says then benefit  That's what happens
when you die, that's the benefit
you choose because your financial banner. How much do
you want to get as a death benefit? Let's say
it's 500,000. So the 500,000
if you die,
that's what your beneficiary will claim.
The Riders or
addons, if you hear them, mean
something like an additional feature to the
Basic or original design insurance.
For example, the only original
feature of the insurance you chose is
death benefit and critical illness, so
you'll have a. I want to have a
Rider that's a
premium waiver. So the premium waiver
is another feature that's
added to your original insurance, but it has an additional payment.
For example, you'll be
disappointed because you have a
premium waiver, so that's a feature
added to your original insurance,
but it has an additional
cost. You'll also hear the
terminologies Grace period, you said
Grace period. This is an extension of
your due date, so most of the time it's
30 days after your due date, so you still have a.
You still have a chance to
pay.  no within the 30 days after
your due date that's just the Grace
period and then when you said
coverage period what I said for
example um 1 year 5 years 10 years um that's all
you're covered for
um policy free lock period this is what
most people don't talk about no
financial advisor after you after
your policy is approved
There is a free look period of 15 days
if you change your mind within 15
days after the policy is approved
You can You can cancel
and you can get your premium back
so there are mostly 15 days and I
think almost all insurance There is that
free look period All
right and lastly ah please hear
the term underwriting
that's the process where
our documents our
requirements are processed no at the
insurance office they will evaluate
our lifestyle our
health condition or the information
like that our personal information
and after underwriting that's where we
will know if
our policy will be approved or not especially
for permanent insurance because
it is long-term and those with
critical illnesses need it.
So underwriting is what is called a
process where we evaluate
our requirements and our
information. Stay tuned for our
next videos so that you will be
more informed you will be more educated
about life insurance and if you have
questions no we are open to questions
just comment down below your question
and inquiries and also You can check the
website of the fwd fwd.com.ph and we have
customer service at our fwt that will
answer you right away no and here in fwd
We will help you no celebrate living and
the vision of
fwd is that people will have a different
perspective about insurance as the role
of gr Grace with KC educating people
what life insurance really is and also
We will help you you understand the
designed um insurance of fwd I hope
we can understand more How important
insurance is in our Uh life individually
because we don't know what will happen
in the future This is grow in Grace with
KC Thank you for watching this video
Thank you for reaching the end of
this video I hope we have learned the
basics  terminologies of life insurance and
ah I'm glad that we can
grow together, let's discuss
money matters, careers and
our dreams in life so that
we can be better towards the
blessings of our Lord
[Music]